engineyard.com 2017-08-05

# Privacy

## Engine Yard Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement sets forth Engine Yard Enterprises, Inc. and its affiliates’ (“Engine Yard”, “we” or “us”) information gathering and dissemination practices regarding personal information collected by Engine Yard directly from individuals (“you”) in connection with the website located at [www.info.engineyard.com](http://info.engineyard.com/) and related URLs (“Website”).

## What We Collect

Engine Yard may collect various types of personal information from you in connection with the Website. Such data may include identifying information and contact information (names, titles, addresses, phone and fax numbers, and email addresses), financial and payment information, information about products and services ordered or provided, IP addresses, and other transaction-related data.

## How We Use Collected Information

###### Contact Information

We may use personal information collected in connection with the Website to contact you regarding products or services you have ordered or are receiving, to send you information about Engine Yard or its partners, to provide services to you, and for other purposes related to our business. You may choose to opt out of receiving communications from us. You will be given this choice at the points on the Website where we request your information. If you do not wish to receive future marketing mailings, please send an e-mail to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com).

###### Financial Information

We may ask you to provide your credit card or other financial account information to enable us to charge your account when you purchase services from us. All information you will be asked to provide is protected during transmission using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption to prevent it from being intercepted as it is transferred over the Internet. We provide this information only to third parties involved in processing payments for the services we provide and as otherwise provided in this Privacy Statement.

###### IP Addresses

We use your unique network address, or IP address, to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer the Website.

###### Cookies

Many of our web pages use “cookies.” Cookies are text files we place in your computer’s browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering at one of our sites. However, once you choose to furnish the site with personal information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our sites. We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs, or services. You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies, please consult the privacy features in your browser.

## Disclosure Of Collected Information

#### Third Parties

Engine Yard may disclose to third parties information we collect from you in connection with the Website (i) as necessary to provide services requested by you, (ii) as necessary to process payments, (iii) to our subcontractors, service providers and other agents in connection with the provision of services to you (provided such subcontractors and service providers are under a duty to maintain the confidentiality of such information), and (iv) in connection with requests from law enforcement officials, government agencies, or otherwise as required in connection with legal proceedings. In addition, we may transfer information we collect from you to a third party in connection with a merger or sale of our business or assets, in which case the resulting entity or transferee will be permitted to obtain and use such information subject to the terms of this Privacy Statement.

#### Web Analytics Services

We use Google Analytics, a service for the marketing analysis of the site provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies to allow us to see how you use our site so we can improve your experience. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use available at http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html and the Google Privacy Policy available at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to the site by disabling cookies in your browser. If you prefer to not have data reported by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

#### Links

We may create links to other web sites. We will make a reasonable effort to link only to sites that meet similar standards for maintaining each individual’s right to privacy. However, many other sites that are not associated with or authorized by Engine Yard may have links leading to our site. Engine Yard cannot control these links and we are not responsible for any content appearing on these sites. Since this website does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy practices of that third party. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose any personal information to others.

#### International Transfers of Personal Data

TInformation collected from you may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Engine Yard or its agents or contractors maintain facilities, and by accessing our sites and using our services, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. For information regarding Engine Yard’s processing of personal data that is stored on Engine Yard’s servers at the direction of Engine Yard’s customers and their end users located in European Union member countries and Switzerland (and that is not collected by Engine Yard directly from individuals via the Website), please see the Engine Yard Privacy Shield Privacy Policy located at https://www.info.engineyard.com/policies/privacyshieldpolicy

## Your Rights

#### Security

Engine Yard implements industry-standard security measures designed to prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, destruction or alteration of the personal information we collect via the Website. However, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. Also, if this website contains links to other sites, Engine Yard is not responsible for the security practices or the content of such sites.

#### Your Access to and Updating of your Personal Information

Reasonable access to your personal information may be provided at no cost upon request made to Engine Yard at the contact information provided below. If access cannot be provided within that time frame, Engine Yard will provide the requesting party a date when the information will be provided. If for some reason access is denied, we will provide an explanation as to why access has been denied.

#### Our Retention of your Personal Information

We will retain any personal information only for as long as is necessary to fulfil the business purpose it was collected. We will also retain and use your personal information for as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Children’s Privacy

Because of the nature of our business, our services are not designed to appeal to minors. We do not knowingly attempt to solicit or receive any information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact us immediately.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

Engine Yard does not currently respond to browser “Do Not Track” (DNT) signals or other mechanisms. Third parties may collect personal information about your online activities over time and across sites when you visit the Website or use the services. If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us by sending an e-mail to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com) Our site, products, and services are not intended to appeal to minors. However, if you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a registered user of our Site or services, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you to request and obtain removal of content or information you have publicly posted. To make such a request, please send an e-mail with a detailed description of the specific content or information to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com). Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested. Under California law, California residents who have an established business relationship with us may opt-out of our disclosing personal information about them to third parties for their marketing purposes.

#### Contacting Us

If you would like to contact Engine Yard regarding the use of your personal information collected in connection with the Website, the types of third parties to whom we disclose such information, ways to limit the use and disclosure of such personal information, or to access, correct, amend, or delete your personal information collected in connection with the Website that is stored on our systems, please send an email to [privacy@engineyard.com](mailto:privacy@engineyard.com)with your request.

#### Changes to our Privacy Statement

Engine Yard may update this Privacy Statement from time to time to reflect changes in its services and customer feedback, and such changes shall become effective promptly after they are posted. Engine Yard encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of any changes. This Privacy Statement was last updated on May 25, 2017.
